MARK FRANCIOSE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SKILLS

TECHNICAL: WordPress, React, AWS (S3, EC2, RDS, more), Javascript, HTML/CSS, Test Driven Development, SQL (postgres, MySQL), PHP, Rails/Ruby

ORGANIZATIONAL LEADERSHIP: Strategic Planning, Leadership Development, Project Management

PROJECTS

Cloud Copier Sep 2017 to Current

- Single page app entirely in Vanilla JS and Python to move files from one cloud service to another.
- Makes use of the APIs for: Dropbox, Google Drive, Microsoft Graph.

Eat Union

May 2017 to Jun 2017

• Single page app restaurant guide. Developed in React, using custom CSS.

Habitual

Aug 2017 to Current

- Project leader for a one week sprint. Built a native mobile productivity app with React Native and a Rails API back end.
- Helps a user maintain healthy habits and visualizes their progress. Interactions with the app's notification take only 1 second.
- Handled deployment, testing, and CI for project.

SUMMARY

At a young age, I was nominated by my peers to take a leadership position in the Union at my last company. I have gained invaluable experience leading people and I am very confident in my ability be placed into a difficult situation and find a viable and efficient solution. I'm looking forward to joining a team that is dynamic, fast-paced, and solving tough problems through code.

CONTACT

 \vee

mark.franciose@gmail.com

techchicago.net

(312) 610-9383

in linkedin.com/in/markfran/

markfranciose

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp Full Stack Development 2017

Purdue University
Political Science and Government 2007

EXPERIENCE

Dev Bootcamp

Chicago, IL

Full Stack Development · May 2017 to Aug 2017

- Completed a 19 week immersive full stack web development course with 1100 + hours of solo and pair programming
- Worked on numerous projects demonstrating agile, testdriven development and good git workflow

Pension Representative

UNITE HERE Local 1 - Chicago, IL

Mar 2016 to May 2017

- Helped to develop safepension.org
- Improved funding status of \$2.1 billion dollar multistakeholder pension fund

Contract Negotiator

UNITE HERE Local 1 - Chicago, IL -

Apr 2012 to Mar 2016

- Maintained and updated individual campaign sites (WordPress)
- Strengthened agreements between key employers (notably McCormick Place and United Center)
- Succeeded working with a variety of different groups, such as city officials, operators, and local management

Organizer / Organizing Trainer UNITE HERE Local 1 - Chicago, IL ·

Mar 2008 to Apr 2012

- Trained numerous junior organizers
- Developed and recruited new members